等等
Wait!
我只想跟你谈谈
I just wanna talk to you.
赶紧走吧 艾克
Get out of here, Ekko.
我只想...
I just...
我只想跟你谈谈 爆...
I just wanna talk to you, Pow--
金克丝
Jinx.
来不及了 艾克
You're too late, Ekko.
等等
Wait!
这节奏我跟不上了
Always a dance with you.
不过我得稍微坐一会儿 缓一缓
I think I'm just gonna sit here a minute.
让我先喘口气
You know, catch my breath.
看看有什么办法 能劝我的老朋友别炸死我俩
See if I can talk an old friend out of blowing us up.
我不想再说了
I'm tired of talking.
不要
No! No! No! No...
以前我认识的一个人
You know, I learned from someone...
她很特别
very special...
她说过去的事 就让它过去 不要纠结
that no matter what happened in the past,
重新开始永远都来得及
it's never too late to build something new.
总有人值得这么做
Someone worth building it for.
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第九集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
我需要你和执法官 尽量为我多争取一点时间
I need you and the Enforcers to buy me as much time as you can
确保我可以关闭海克斯飞门
so I can shut down the Hexgates.
机会只有一次
It's our only chance.
维克托是一切的始作俑者 对不对
Viktor's at the center of all this, isn't he?
我们本来就没有什么胜算
We're meant to lose this fight.
要是他到了海克斯飞门的话
If he reaches the Hexgates...
那就尽全力阻止他
Then we'd best stop him.
快走
Move, move!
派增援保护远程火力
Reinforce the forward artillery.
- 绝不能让他们攻进来 - 去吧
- We can't let them break through. - Go.
我们走
Let's go.
把大门关上
- Hold it. - Go.
上弹药
Reload.
把她面具拿掉 你怎么样
- Give her some air. - You're okay.
趴下
Down!
快点
Come on.
快走
Let's go.
人不大 胆儿不小啊
Bold, little one.
- 带上你的人 随时待命 - 先等等
- Move your units and wait there. - Stay.
快点
Come on!
我提醒过你公私不分会是什么下场
I warned you of the hazards of professional entanglement.
铤而走险 只会让你万劫不复 孩子
Desperation is the doorway to oblivion, child.
赶紧了结了吧
Let's get this over with.
我会念着你对我的好
I did appreciate your warmth.
如果你心里还在乎我 那就饶他们一命
If you care for me at all, spare their lives.
这样的杀戮根本没有任何意义 而你也什么也得不到
There is nothing to gain from this senseless bloodshed.
还是想当狐狸
Still a fox.
士兵
Soldier.
列队
Get in line.
开火
Fire!
跟我走
Let's run.
维克托在哪儿
Where is Viktor?
即便走到了今天这般田地 杰斯
Despite the circumstances, Jayce...
我依然很高兴与你会面
I am... pleased to see you.
我不相信曾经的那个你已经完全不在
There must be some part of you still in there.
现在的我所向披靡
I am more than I ever was.
母亲
Mother,
看看你为野心付出的代价
look at the price of your ambition.
牺牲一切都在所不惜
You've sacrificed everything.
雷克托斯
Rictus.
基诺
Kino.
我为了家族建起的这座城邦
This city I built for our family.
你要真为了家族 就不会与我为敌
If it was for us, you wouldn't have fought me.
你不配姓米达尔达
You are no Medarda.
还记得你的...
You remember your--
少废话 动手吧
Shut up and fight.
蔚
Vi!
这就是你跟我倾尽一生所追求的答案
It is the answer you and I pursued all our lives.
消除所有残暴 所有不公
An end to cruelty, injustice.
我们每一个人都参与其中 轮流撰写着这个进化传奇
All of us our own authors to an unbroken saga of progress.
我们每一个人都从中获益
To the benefit of all.
每一个人的命运都应该由自己选择
People deserve to choose their own fates.
选择并不存在
Choice is false.
那只是一种说辞而已
It is how we clothe and forgive
用来掩盖和宽恕 令我们产生分歧的本能
the baser instincts that spur us to division.
比如死亡 战争 还有偏见
Death, war, prejudice.
这个过程也只不过是一种能量内耗
Energy spent only to consume itself.
然而我们能实现的是
But we can be of one mind.
众心归一
United.
虽败犹荣 孩子
You fought well, child.
动手
Now!
狼本就冷血无情
A wolf has no mercy.
你女儿比你想象的更有智慧
Your daughter is wiser than you credit.
我敬佩你 安蓓萨
I salute you, Ambessa.
虽是凡夫俗子
For one without the gift,
却令我们感到棘手
you were quite a thorn.
你来干什么 姐妹
What are you doing, sister?
你的真面目我认清了 骗子
I see your face, deceiver.
算你聪明
Sly girl.
你是真正的狼
You are the wolf.
看样子你不应该回来的
Looks like you shouldn't have come back.
你还是不明白啊 姐姐
Still don't get it, huh, sis?
我和你从来没有分开过
I'm always with you.
即便我们天各一方
Even when we're worlds apart.
结束这场闹剧吧 维克托
Stop this insanity, Viktor.
说得没错 我也正有此意
That is precisely my intention.
你的眼睛骗不了人
Your eyes won't lie...
你的心已经被
when your mind...
打开了 杰斯
is open, Jayce.
范德尔
Vander.
爸爸
Dad?
看到了吗
Do you see?
一场秩序与混乱前所未有的极致碰撞
The sublime intersection of order and chaos.
这就是你所看到的吗
This is what you see?
这场纷争
This conflict.
这种毫无意义的消耗
This senseless waste.
我了解他们的内心 杰斯
I know their minds, Jayce.
他们渴望更好的生活 而情感与理智却在对抗
They want better lives, but emotion clashes with reason.
这其实是人性走向堕落的内在矛盾
Humanity's self-corrupting contradiction.
你始终执着于弥补你认为不足的东西
You've always wanted to cure what you thought were weaknesses.
你的腿
Your leg.
还有你的病
Your disease.
但那不是你的缺陷 维克托
But you were never broken, Viktor.
不完美本身也有它自己的美
There is beauty in imperfections.
它是你无法割舍的一部分
They made you who you are.
也正是因为有了它 才有了完整的你
An inseparable piece of everything...
这样的你令我钦佩
I admired about you.
那个装置 不可能
That device can't be.
我曾希望你我可以将魔法带给世界
I thought I wanted us to give magic to the world.
但现在 我只希望
Now... all I want...
我的搭档可以回来
is my partner back.
你为什么要如此执着
Why do you persist?
毕竟我做了那么多事
After everything I've done?
因为我答应过你
Because I promised you.
为什么你要给我这个
Why did you ever give me this?
为什么
Why?
我曾以为自己能终结这世上的疾苦
I thought I could bring an end to the world's suffering.
而当我解决了所有难题之后
But when every equation was solved...
前方迎接我的
all that remained...
只剩一片无梦的孤寂
were fields of dreamless solitude.
实现完美并无奖赏
There is no prize to perfection.
追求完美却有终点
Only an end to pursuit.
在所有的时间线里
In all timelines,
在这一切的可能中
in all possibilities...
只有你
only you...
能让我看清这点
can show me this.
你该走了 杰斯
You must go, Jayce.
我们一起结束这一切
We finish this together.
蔚
Vi!
蔚 快跳到那根横梁上去
Vi, hurry, you can make the other ledge.
蔚
Vi!
你这是...
What are you...?
蔚
Vi.
Vi?
你救不了他的
You can't save him.
蔚
Vi!
我一直都在
Always with you, sis.
或许你曾读到过皮尔特沃夫之战
You may read about the war in Piltover.
但历史总是被轻描淡写 一笔带过
But history is made palatably abstract.
而在现实中
For its truth...
每一次牺牲的悲痛哀嚎
the agony of every sacrifice...
每一次胜利的热泪盈眶
the exaltation of every triumph...
都非常人所能承受
is more than one should bear.
曾经种种 造就了我们的今天
We... whose decisions led us here,
也将烙印在我们的余生里
will carry them forever.
欣慰的是在每一次的失去中
Our only consolation that with every loss,
都能寻回善良
we found some good,
重见光明
some light,
这些收获
worth gaining,
值得奋力一搏
worth fighting for.
或许我们还是会重复曾经犯过的错误
And though we are doomed to revisit the error of our ways...
燃起更多的战火
spark ever more conflicts...
我们的故事仍未结束
our story isn't over.
(海克斯飞门 由杰斯塔利斯设计)
(风道与冷却系统)
这是在哼什么呢
Is that... singing?
这个调子我妈妈以前经常哼
It's just a tune my mother used to hum.
还会与我并肩作战吗 蔚奥莱
Are you still in this fight, Violet?
我就是你指甲缝里的泥 小蛋糕
I am the dirt under your nails, cupcake.
怎么洗都洗不掉
Nothing's gonna clean me out.
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻